the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT that EDU ha in
麻省理工学院的EDU公顷
in
the
该
the in
在该
the moon
月亮
the
该
over the last several lectures we developed the for a representation for
在过去的几个讲座，我们开发了用于一个表示
and continuous-time signals what i'd
和连续时间信号就是我想要
now like to do is develop a similar representation for discrete-time
现在想要做的是制定离散时间了类似的表示
and let me begin a discussion by
并让我开始一个讨论
reminding you up what are basic motivation was the idea
提醒您什么是基本的动机，他的想法
is that what we wanted to do was exploit the properties
就是我们想要做的是什么剥削性质
love linearity in time and variance for linear time-invariant systems
爱的线性时间和方差的线性时不变系统
so and in the case love
所以，该情况下的爱
linear time-invariant systems the
线性时不变系统
basic idea was to consider
基本思路是考虑
decomposing the input as a linear combination
分解所述输入的线性组合
love basic inputs and then
爱的基本输入，然后
because I've Lenny arity the output could be expressed as
因为我莱尼元数的输出可表示为
a linear combination of corresponding outputs where
的相应的输出的线性组合，其中
saw I serve I is the output
看到我为我是输出
due to fee survive so
由于费生存如此
basically what we attempted to do was decompose the input
基本上我们试图做的是分解输入
and then reconstruct the output through
然后通过重构输出
a linear combination all the outputs to those basic inputs
线性组合的所有输出到这些基本的输入
we then focused on the notion
我们然后聚焦在概念
love choosing the basic inputs
爱选择的基本输入
with two criterion mine one was
有两个标准矿之一是
to choose them so that a broad class signals
选择它们，这样一个广泛的一类信号
could be constructed out over those basic inputs
可以对这些基本的输入构造出
and the second was to choose the basic inputs
第二是选择的基本输入
so that the response to those was easy to compute
使得响应于那些容易被计算
and as you recall one representation that we ended up with
正如你记得，我们结束了一个代表性
with those basic criteria in mind:
考虑到这些基本准则：
was the representation through convolution
是通过卷积的代表性
and then in beginning the discussion love the for a representation of
然后在开始讨论爱的的表示
continuous-time signals
连续时间信号
we chose as another said a basic inputs
我们选择了作为一个人说一个基本的输入
complex exponentials so
复指数的声音
for continuous-time we chose
对于连续时间我们选择
a set love basic inputs which were complex exponential
一套基本的爱投入其中是复指数
the motivation there was the fact that
动机有一个事实，即
the complex exponentials have we referred to as
该复指数已经我们简称为
the I can function property namely
在我能即功能属性
if we put complex exponentials into our continuous-time systems
如果我们把复杂的指数函数到我们的连续时间系统
than the output is a complex exponential
比输出是一个复指数
love the same form with
爱相同的形式与
only a change in complex amplitude
在复杂的振幅只改变
and that change in complex amplitude is
而在复杂的振幅变化是
what we referred to as the
我们称
frequency response %uh the system
频率响应％呃系统
and also by the way as it developed later
并且还顺便因为它后来发展
that frequency response as you should now recognize from this expression
该频率响应，你现在应该从这个表达式识别
is in fact the 48 transform the continuous-time for EA transform
实际上是在48变换的连续时间为EA变换
all the system impulse response and
所有的系统脉冲响应和
the notion all decomposing a signal as a linear combination of both these complex
所有分解的信号为这两个复杂的线性组合的概念
exponentials
指数函数
is what the first the forty a series
是第一个四系列
representation and then later the Fourier transform representation
表示再后来傅立叶变换表示
corresponded to
符合
and finally to remind you
最后提醒你
love one additional point the fact is that because the eigenfunction property
爱一个额外的一点事实是，因为本征函数属性
the response
响应
once we decompose the input as a linear combination
一旦我们分解输入的线性组合
complex exponentials the response to that when your combination
复指数的反应，当你的组合
is straightforward to compute once we know the frequency response
是简单的计算，一旦我们知道了频率响应
because if the eigenfunction property now
因为如果现在的本征函数属性
basically the same strategy
基本相同的策略
and many of the same ideas work in discrete-time
和许多相同的工作思路在离散时间
paralleling almost exactly what happened in continuous-time
并联几乎完全发生了什么事在连续时间
so the similarities between discrete-time and continuous-time
所以离散时间和连续时间之间的相似性
are very strong although as we'll see there are a number
是非常强的，虽然我们会看到有一些
a differences and it's important
一个区别，它是重要的
as we go through the discussion to illuminate
当我们经过讨论，照亮
not only the similarities but obviously also the differences
不仅相似之处，但也明显的差异
well let's begin with the I can function property
好，让我们开始与我的功能属性
and let me just say that just as in continuous-time
让我只想说，就像在连续时间
if we consider said a basic signals
如果我们考虑说，一个基本的信号
which are complex exponentials
这是复指数
then discrete-time linear time-invariant systems
那么离散时间线性时不变系统
have the I can function property namely
有我可以即功能属性
if we put a complex exponential into the system
如果我们把一个复杂的指数进入系统
the response is a complex exponential
该反应是一个复指数
at the same complex frequency and
在相同的复合频率和
simply multiplied by inappropriate
简单地乘以不当
complex factor or constant
复杂因素或不变
and just as we did in
而正如我们在做
continuous-time we will be
连续时间，我们将
referring to this complex constant which is a function
参照这个复杂的常数，它的功能
of course the frequency other complex exponential input
当然还有其他的频率复指数输入
will be referring to this as the frequency response
将参照此作为频率响应
and although it's not particularly evident at this point
并且，虽然它不是特别明显在这一点上
as the discussion develops through this lecture what in fact will happen
作为讨论通过这个讲座，其实会发生什么发展
is very much paralleling
非常多并联
continuous-time this particular expression
连续时间这个特殊的表达
in fact will correspond
其实将对应
to what will refer to as the
什么将引用为
for EA transform the discrete-time Fourier transform
对于EA变换的离散时间傅里叶变换
up the system impulse response so there of course there's a very strong parallel
了系统的脉冲响应所以当然有一个非常强大的并行
between continuous-time and discrete-time
连续时间和离散时间之间
now just as we did in continuous-time
现在，正如我们在连续时间做
let's begin a discussion by
让我们通过开始讨论
first concentrating on periodic the representation through complex
首先通过复杂的集中在周期性的代表性
exponentials
指数函数
love periodic sequences and then
爱周期序列，然后
will generalize that discussion to the representation
将概括地说，讨论的代表性
Ave periodic signals so
AVE所以周期信号
let's consider furs a periodic signal
让我们考虑皮草周期信号
or in general signals which are periodic
或在一般信号是周期性
period to notify capital and and then
期限通知的资本和再
course the fundamental frequency is
当然，基本频率为
to pie divided by capital
以饼除以资本
now we can consider exponentials
现在我们可以考虑指数函数
which have this as a fundamental frequency
其中有这样一个基本频率
war which are harmonics that
战争，是谐波，
and that would correspond to the class of complex exponentials
并且将对应于该类别的复指数
the form you to the JK Omega 0n
表单您的JK欧米茄0N
so these complex exponentials then
所以这些复指数则
as k varies are complex exponentials
当k而变复指数
that are harmonically related with
这是和谐与相关
all of which our periodic with the same period
所有这一切我们定期与上年同期
capital and although the fundamental period
资本和虽然基本周期
is different for each of these each of them being related by
是他们每个人的这些由每所涉及的不同
an integer amount
一个整数金额
now again just as we did in continuous time we can consider
现在又只是因为我们没有在连续的时间，我们可以考虑
attempting to build our periodic signal I have a linear combination
试图建立我们的周期信号我有一个线性组合
love these and so we consider
喜欢这些，所以我们考虑
a periodic signal which is
一个周期性信号，它是
a weighted sum all these
加权和所有这些
me complex exponentials and
我复指数和
of course this periodic signal this is a periodic signal as can be
当然这个周期信号，这是一个周期性的信号，作为可
verified in more or less in a straightforward way by substitution
在用替换一个简单的方法或多或少验证
and of course one of the things that will want to address shortly
当然，这将要在短期内解决的事情之一
is how broad a classic signals again can be represented
是多么广阔的经典信号再次可以表示
by this psalm and another question obviously will be
通过这诗篇和另外一个问题显然会
how do we determine the coefficients a suitcase
我们如何确定系数手提箱
however in before we do that let me
但是在之前我们这样做让我
focus on an important distinction
专注于一个重要的区别
between continuous-time and discrete-time
连续时间和离散时间之间
in the context of these complex exponentials and this representation
在这些复指数的情况下，这表示
when we talked about complex exponentials and sinusoids
当我们谈到复指数和血窦
early in the cores one up the difference is that we saw between continuous-time
在芯早1升的不同之处在于，我们看到连续时间之间
and discrete-time
和离散时间
is dead in continuous-time as we very
是死在连续时间，因为我们很
in the frequency variable we see different complex exponentials
在频率变量，我们看到不同的复指数
as Omega berries whereas in discrete-time
欧米茄浆果，而在离散时间
we saw in fact dead there was a period this city
我们其实看到很多死人有一段这个城市
or said another way it's straightforward to verify
或者说另一种方式是直接验证
that if we think I love this
如果我们觉得我喜欢这个
class a complex exponentials day
一类复指数一天
in fact if we consider burying
事实上，如果我们考虑埋
K by an ink to it
由墨K到它
capital and where capital and is the period
资本与地方资本，是周期
all the fundamental
所有基本
complex exponential then in fact
指数再复杂，其实
if we replace K by K plus capital and
如果我们替代了k以K加资本和
we'll see exactly the same complex exponentials over again
我们将看到完全一样的复指数一遍
now what does that say what it says is that if I consider this class of complex
现在到底是什么说什么它说的是，如果我认为这个类的复杂
exponentials
指数函数
SK varies from zero
SK从零变化
through capital N -1 we've seen
通过资本N-1，我们已经看到
we will see all of the ones that there are two see
我们会看到所有的那些有两个见
there aren't any more and so in fact
有没有任何事实越来越使
if we can build excessive and
如果我们能够建立和过多
I have this linear combination then
我有这样的线性组合，然后
we better be able to do it as k varies
我们最好是能够做到这一点随着k变化
from 0
从0
up to and -1 because
达和-1，因为
beyond that will simply see the same complex s
除此之外，只会看到相同的复杂s
exponentials over again so for example
指数函数一遍这样的例子
if k takes on the value capital and
如果k取值为资本和
that will be exactly the same complex exponential
这将是完全相同的复指数
as if KZ 0
仿佛KZ 0
so in fact this some ranges
所以其实这方面的一些范围
only over capital in above the distinct complex exponentials
只有在资本上面的不同的复指数
let's say for example from 0 to capital and -1
比方说，例如，从0到资本和-1
although in fact since these complex exponentials repeat
但事实上，因为这些复指数重复
in K I could actually consider instead have
以K我其实可以考虑，而不是有
from 0 to N -1 I could consider from one
从0到N-1，我可以考虑从一个
and or from to too and plus one or whatever
和或过多及加一或什么
or said another way in this representation
或所述另一种方式在此表示
I could alternatively shoes K
我可以交替鞋Ķ
outside this range thinking
在此范围之外的思维
0 these coefficients simply as periodically repeating in K
0这些系数只是作为定期重复以K
because if the fact that these complex exponentials
因为如果一个事实，即这些复指数
periodically repeating K so in fact
周期性地重复ķ所以实际上
in place if this expression it will be comin in writing the forty a series
在地方，如果这个表达式将被科曼以书面的40系列
expression
表达
to write it as i've indicated here where the implication is
写它，因为我已经在这里指出其中的含义是
that these Fourier coefficients
这些傅立叶系数
periodically repeated as K continues to rip
定期重复以K继续撕裂
to repeat outside the interval from 0 to N -1
向间隔之外重复从0到N-1
and so this notation in fact says
所以这个符号其实说
at what we're going to use are
在我们将要使用的是什么
is K ranging over one period
为k的范围在一个周期内
love this periodic sequence which is the forty a series called
喜欢这个周期序列也就是40了一系列名为
visions okay so
愿景没关系使
the expression that we have been for the forty a series
我们一直在为40系列的表达
I've repeated here and the implication now is that
我在这里重复的含义是，现在
the AC K's are periodic they periodically repeat because of course
交流K公司的当然是因为他们定期重复周期性
these exponentials periodically repeated
这些指数函数周期性重复
this indicates there we only use them over one period
这表明有我们只使用其中一个周期
and now we can inquire as to how
现在我们可以询问如何
we determine the coefficients aces K
我们确定系数尖子Ķ
well we can formally go through this much as we did in
好，我们可以正式通过这个多，因为我们在做
the continuous-time case in and 0
连续时间的情况下在0和
we do in fact do that in the text which involves substituting some
我们实际上做到这一点，其中包括取代一些文字
sums in a change in yours summation cetera
金额在你的求和等等的变化
but let me a draw your attention to the fact that
但让我提请你注意这样的事实：
this in fact can be thought I love
这实际上可以认为我爱
as capital in equations in capital and unknowns
作为资本在资本和未知方程
in other words we know x7 over a period
换句话说，我们知道X7一段
and so we know what the left hand side if this is for capital and bad news
所以我们知道左手侧，如果这是资本和坏消息
and we'd like to determine these constant sese K
我们想确定这些常数塞塞Ķ
well it turns out that their is a nice convening in closed form expression for
还有事实证明，他们是一个很好的召开闭合形式表达式
that
那
and in fact if we evaluate the closed-form expression
而事实上，如果我们评估的封闭形式表达
through any variety of algebraic manipulations
通过任何各种代数运算的
we end up then with the
我们最后再与
analysis equation and the analysis equation
分析方程和分析方程
which tells us how to get the coefficients AC K
它告诉我们如何系数交流Ķ
from excessive and is what I've
过度的，是我所
indicated here and
此处显示和
so this tells us how for Maxim and
所以这告诉我们如何为Maxim和
to get the AC K's and of course the first equation
得到的AC K公司的，当然第一方程
tells us how x7 is built up by the VA's
告诉我们如何X7是建立了由VA的
K's notice incidently that
K公司的通知，顺便说一句是
there is a strong to our the between these two equations
有较强的对我们的这两个方程之间
and that's a duality that will return to
，这是一个双重性，将返回到
actually toward the end of the next lecture now
其实现在朝下一讲座结束
there is a real difference between the way those equations look
也就是这样，那些看起来方程之间的真正区别
and the way the continuous-time forty a series look
和方法的连续时间40的一系列外观
in a continuous-time case let me remind you
在一个连续时间的情况下，让我提醒你
that it required
它需要
an infinite number of coefficients to build up this continuous-time
系数来建立这个连续时间无限数量
function and so this was not simply a matter
功能，所以这不是一个简单的事情
of identifying how to invert capital and
如何识别反转资本和
were a finite number of equations in a finite number upon owns
为方程中时有限数量有限数量的拥有
and the analysis equation was
和分析方程为
and integration as opposed to the synthesis equation
和整合，而不是合成公式
which is a summation so
这是一个求和所以
their is a real difference there between
他们之间是否有一个真正的区别
the continuous-time and discrete-time cases and a difference
连续时间和离散时间情况和差别
arises to a large extent because
产生在很大程度上是因为
all this notion that in discrete-time the complex exponentials
这一切的概念，即在离散时间的复指数
are periodic in
是周期性的
their frequency so we have been to summarize
它们的频率，所以我们一直总结
the synthesis equation and the analysis equation
合成方程和分析方程
for the discrete-time for a series
对于离散时间的一系列
again x7 are original signals periodic
再次X7是原来的信号周期
and of course the complex exponentials
和当然的复指数
involve the periodic their periodic obviously in an
包括定期的周期性明显的
by it in contrast the continuous-time these repeat
通过将其在相反的连续时间这些重复
in K in other words as k Omega 0
以K换句话说，当k欧米茄0
goes outside arrange that covers a 25 interval
去外面安排，涵盖了25间隔
and because if that we're imposing
因为如果我们正在实施
in a sense the interpretation that the AC Kesar likewise the periodic sequence
在一定意义上诠释了交流凯萨尔同样的周期序列
and in fact we look at the analysis equation
而事实上我们看看分析方程
as we let K very
我们令K很
outside the range from 0 to N -1
从0到N-1的范围外
what you can easily verified by substitution in here
你可以通过替换在这里轻松地验证
is that this sequence will in fact periodically repeat
是，该序列将实际上周期性地重复
so to underscore the difference between the continuous-time and discrete-time
因此要强调的连续时间和离散时间之间的差
cases
例
we have this periodicity in the time domain
有这样的周期性的时域
and that's a periodicity dad is of course true in discrete-time
，这是一个周期性的爸爸当然是真的在离散时间
and it's also true in continuous-time
而且它也确实在连续时间
if we replace the integer variable
如果我们更换整型变量
by the discrete-time time variable
通过离散时间的时间可变
and we also indiscreet I'm have this periodicity
我们也指手画脚，我有这样的周期性
in krak Omega 0 and correspondingly
在KRAK欧米茄0，相应
a periodicity in the four EA coefficients
在4 EA系数的周期性
and bad is center properties
坏的是中心物业
dat does not happen
逸不会发生
in continuous-time and is bad
在连续时间和是坏
there essentially leads to all of the important differences between
有本质上导致所有的之间的重要区别
discrete-time Fourier representations and in continuous-time
离散时间傅里叶陈述和连续时间
Korea representation
韩国代表性
now just quickly let me draw your attention to the issue
现在只是快让我提请你注意的问题
love convergence and when a sequence can and can't be represented at cetera
爱收敛，当一个序列可以与不能在等等为代表
a recall that in the continuous-time case
召回，在连续时间的情况下
we focused on convergence in the context either
我们专注于融合的背景下，无论是
conditions which are referred to as where the group believe the
这被称为倘本集团相信条件
or another set of conditions which were the the Ridgeway conditions
或另一组条件是在里奇韦条件
and there was this issue about when the signal doesn't doesn't convergent
并且有这样的问题有关，当信号不不收敛
discontinuities
不连续
center let me just simply draw your attention to the fact
中心让我简单地提请你注意这样的事实：
there in the discrete-time case
有在离散时间情况
what we have is the representation of the periodic signal
我们所拥有的是周期信号的表示
as Assam all a finite number
阿萨姆所有数量有限
turns this represents capital and equations in capital and unknowns
原来这代表资本，资本和未知方程
if we consider the partial some namely taking
如果我们考虑的部分，即一些服用
a smaller number turns then simply what happens
一个较小的匝数然后简单地会发生什么
is as the number of turns increases
是因为匝数增加
to the finite number required to represent
到表示所需要的有限数量的
ex-dividend we simply end up with
除息我们只是结束了
the partial some representing the fun and Lightsey
部分代表的一些乐趣和Lightsey
were all that boils down to is the statement
都归结为是语句
that in discrete-time there really are
在离散时间真的有
no convergence issues as they were in continues time
没有，因为他们是在收敛问题持续时间
okay well let's look at an example love the four EA
好吧那么让我们来看一个例子爱的四个EA
series representation for a particular signal
对于一个特定的信号序列表示
and the one that I think here is a simple one
和一个我认为这里是一个简单的
namely a constant a
即恒定的一个
are signed term and a cosine term
签署长期和余弦项
now for this particular example we can expand this out
现在这个特殊的例子中，我们可以扩大这一点，
directly in terms of complex exponentials
直接在复指数方面
and essentially recognize this as a somewhat complex exponentials
而且基本上认识到这是一个有点复杂的指数函数
its examined in more detail
其更详细地考察
in example 5.2 in attacks
例如5.2在袭击中
and if we looked at the for a series coefficients we can either look
如果我们看了一个级数的系数，我们可以看
at it in terms of real and imaginary parts are magnitude and angle
在它的实部和虚部分条款幅度和角度
on the left side here I have the real part of the 48 coefficients
左侧在这里我有48系数的实部
and let me draw your attention to the fact
让我提请您注意以下事实：
their I've drawn yes
他们的我画是
to specifically illuminate the periodicity
具体照亮周期
other for a series coefficients in with a period of capital and so here are the
其他在用了一段资本的一系列系数，所以这里的
Fourier coefficients
傅立叶系数
are and in fact its this line that represents the DCR constant term
是，事实上它的这条线，代表该DCR常数项
and these two lines represent the
和这两条线表示
co-signed term and of course this
共同签署了期限，当然，这
these are the three turns that are required or equivalent leave this one
这些都是需要或等效的三圈离开这个
this one
这一个
and this one and then because the period this city
而这一次，然后因为这个时期城市
the for a series coefficients this simply periodically repeats
在为一系列系数这只是周期性重复
so here is the real part and below it I show
所以这里是实部和它下面我展示
the imaginary part and
虚数部分和
in the imaginary part incidently let me
在虚部顺便说一句让我
draw your attention to the fact dead its
提请您注意以下事实：死者的
this term and this term
这个词和这个词
there represent in the imaginary part that represent the sinusoid
有代表在代表正弦曲线的虚部
whereas its the symmetric turns the real part
而它的对称转动的实部
the represent the cosine okay let's
该代表余弦好吧，让的
in look at another example
在看看另外一个例子
this is another example from the tax and one
这是从税收和另一个例子
that will be making frequent reference to
将要进行频繁参考
in this particular lecture
在这个特定的演讲
and what it is is
并且它是什么
a square wave and
一个方波和
I've express the for a series coefficients which are out algebraically
我已经表达了对一系列系数的都出来了代数
developed in attacks
在开发攻击
I've expressed the for a series coefficients as
我已经表达了对一系列系数为
samples all an envelope
所有样品的信封
function and so I've expressed that as samples if this
功能，所以我已经表示，作为样本，如果这
particular function which is referred to as a sign
这被称为一个标志特定功能
enacts over sin x function and let me just compare it
颁布了罪X功能，让我只是比较它
to a continuous-time example which is the
到连续时间的例子，是
continuous-time square wave
连续时间的方波
where with the continuous times square wave
凡与本次连续的方波
the form or the for a series coefficients
的形式或为一系列系数
was as samples love what we refer to
是作为样本热爱我们参考
as a sin x over expunge
作为一种罪过倍过EXPUNGE
now the sin NX
现在罪恶的NX
over sin x function which is the envelope for the for a series
过罪x函数，它是信封的一个系列
coefficients
系数
for the discrete-time periodic square wave
对于离散时间周期性方波
plays the role and we'll see it very often in discrete-time
所扮演的角色，我们会看到它经常在离散时间
that sin x over exercise in continuous-time
罪x在运动中连续时间
and in fact we should understand right from the beginning
而事实上，我们应该明白从一开始
that the sin x over extend below couldn't possibly be
该罪x在下方延伸不可能是
the envelope the discrete-time for a series coefficients
包络线的离散时间为一系列系数
and one obvious reason is dead
，一个显而易见的原因是死的
it is not periodic what we require of course
我们要求，当然这不是周期性
from the discussion I just going through is periodicity
从讨论中我刚刚经历的周期性
are the coefficients and consequently also periodicity of the envelope
是系数，因而也是周期性的信封
in the discrete-time case so once again if we look back
在离散时间情况下，再一次让我们回头看
at the algebraic expression that I have
在代数表达式，我有
it samples about the sign an X over sin x
大约过罪x符号的X是样本
function dead represent the for a series coefficients
功能死者为代表的一系列系数
love this periodic square way
喜欢这种周期性的方方式
now in the representation in
现在在表示
the continuous-time case we
连续时间情况下，我们
essentially head use the concept of an envelope
基本上头使用一个信封的概念
to represent the for a series coefficients
表示为一系列系数的
and the notion that the for a series coefficients were samples
和概念，即对一系列系数分别为样品
up an envelope and that is said the same notion
了一个信封，说是说了同样的概念
there will be using in discrete-time so
那里将使用在离散时间，以便
again for this square wave example
再次为这个方波的例子
then what we have is an envelope
那么我们所拥有的是一个信封
function the sign acts
功能符号行为
over sin x envelope function for
过罪x包络函数为
a particular value of the period here indicated with a period
此处的周期的特定值表示与一期
love 10 samples these
10爱这些样本
samples at this envelope function with then
在这个包络函数与当时的样本
represent the for a series coefficients
表示为一系列系数的
if we increased
如果我们增加
the period then
期间再
we would simply have a finer spacing
我们只会有一个更细的间距
on the samples are the envelope function
对样品的包络函数
to get the 40 a series coefficients and
以获得40的一系列系数和
in likewise if we increase the period still further
在同样如果我们增加周期进一步
what we would have is an even finer space
我们所拥有的是一个更精细的空间
so actually as the period increases recall we use this in the in
所以实际上随着周期增加记得我们用这个在中
continuous-time also
连续时间也
as the period increases we can view the for a series coefficients
随着周期的增加，我们可以查看一系列系数
samples of an envelope and as the period increases
一个信封，作为周期增加样本
the sample spacing gets finer and finer
采样间距变得越来越精细
and in fact as the period goes
而事实上作为周期变
of essentially to infinity the samples of the envelope
基本上到无穷大信封样品
in effect become the anvil and recall also
实际上成为砧，也记得
that this was essentially the trip that we use
这基本上是我们使用的旅程
in continuous-time to allow us
在连续时间允许我们
to develop or utilize the 48 series
开发或利用48系列
to provide a representation %uh a periodic signals
提供一种表示％呃一个周期性信号
as a linear combination of complex exponentials
为复指数的线性组合
in particular what we did in
特别是我们在做
the continuous-time case
连续时间的情况下
when we head and a periodic signal
当我们的头和一个周期信号
was to consider constructing a periodic signal
是要考虑建设周期信号
for which be a periodic signal was one period
对于这是一个周期信号是一个周期
and then we developed the notion there since
然后我们开发的概念，因为有
the periodic signal has a forty eight series
的周期信号具有48系列
and since as the period
既然作为期
the periodic signal increases n goes to infinity
周期信号增加n趋于无穷大
the periodic signal represents the a periodic signal
周期信号表示的周期信号
then essentially the 48 series
然后基本上是48系列
provides us with the representation now
为我们提供了表示现在
we can do exactly the same thing in the discrete-time case
我们可以做同样的事情在离散时间情况
the statement is exactly the same except dead in a discrete-time case
该语句是完全相同的，除了死在离散时间情况
instead of see as the independent variable
而不是看作为独立变量
we simply make exactly the same statement
我们只是做完全一样的语句
but with are discrete-time variable
但是是离散时间变量
and so the basic notion then in representing
等等基本概念，然后在代表
a discrete-time a periodic signal
离散时间周期信号
is to first construct
是先构造
a periodic signal here we have the
周期信号在这里，我们有
a periodic signal reconstruct a periodic signal
一个周期信号重构的周期信号
by simply periodically replicating the a periodic signal
通过简单地周期性地复制的周期信号
the periodic signal in the a periodic signal are identical
的周期信号的周期信号是相同的
for one period and as
一期和
the period goes off to infinity
期间熄灭到无限远
it's the forty a series representation of the periodic signal
它是40的周期信号的一个级数表示
that provides a representation all
它提供了一个代表所有
the a periodic signal again
的周期信号再次
to returned to the example
以返回到示例
that we
我们
have been kinda working through this lecture namely the periodic square wave
已还挺通过这个讲座的工作即周期性方波
if we have in a periodic signal which is a rectangle
如果我们有一个周期性信号，它是一个矩形
and reconstruct the periodic signal
和重建的周期信号
and now we consider letting this period increase to infinity
现在我们可以考虑让这个时期增加至无穷远
we would first have this set of samples of the envelope
我们首先这套信封样品
as the period increases we would decrease the sample spacing to this set
随着周期的增加，我们将减少采样间隔这一套
of samples
样品
as the period increases further it would be
作为周期进一步增加这将是
this set of samples and as the period goes off to infinity
这组样品和期间熄灭到无限远
its every point on the envelope in fact
其信封，其实在每一个点
what the representation up the a periodic signal
什么样的表示了一个周期性的信号
is is the anvil
是是砧
okay well so that's the basic notion it's no different than what we did
好舒服，所以这是最基本的概念，它比我们所做的没有什么不同
in the continuous-time case and
在连续时间的情况下，并
mathematically it develops in
数学上它的发展
very much the same way as in the continuous-time
非常相同的方式在连续的时间
case specifically
具体情况
here is our representation
这里是我们的代表性
through the forty a series all the
通过40系列的所有
here here's a representation through the envelope function
在这里这里是通过包络函数的表示
and this is the 48 series synthesis equation where
这是48系列的合成公式，其中
equation the equation below tells us
等式如下方程告诉我们
how we'd get these for EA coefficients
我们如何会得到这些对EA系数
or the envelope from accident
或因意外信封
now extolled event is the periodic signal and we know that
现在阐扬事件是周期信号，我们知道，
over one period which is the only interval over which we use it
在一个周期的结束，我们使用它的唯一间隔
in fact this is identical to the a periodic signal
实际上这是相同的周期信号
its own fact we can rewrite this equation
自己的事实，我们可以重写这个等式
simply by substituting instead effect told The
只需通过替换，而不是效果告诉
the original a periodic signal and now
原始周期信号和现在
we can use infinite limits on this some and
我们可以用一些这方面的无限的限制和
what we would want to examine mathematically is
我们所要研究的数学就是
what happens to the top equation
恰好顶方程是什么
as to the top equation as we let the period
作为顶端的公式，因为我们要让期
go off to infinity and what happens is
熄灭到无穷大，什么情况是
exactly identical mathematically to continuous-time
数学上连续时间完全相同
I won't the labor the details essentially
我不会劳动的本质细节
its this some that goes to an integral
其本有的认为去一个组成
Omega 0 which is the fundamental frequency is going
ω-0，这是基本频率会
toward zero in fact becomes the differential in the integral
朝向实际上零变成在积分的微分
and in the second equation of course this then becomes excessive Omega
而在课程的第二个方程这便成为欧米茄过度
and as n goes to infinity then
而当n趋于无穷然后
what the for a series becomes is the 48 transform
什么样的一个系列变成是48变换
as summarized by the bottom to
总结由底至
equations so although
方程所以虽然
there are is a little bit mathematical
有一点点数学
trickery year but I called trickery but subtlety
挂羊头卖狗肉一年，但我叫挂羊头卖狗肉，但微妙
to be tracked through in detail the important conceptual thing to think
要通过详细的跟踪重要的概念性的东西去思考
about
关于
is this notion dead
这是死的概念
we take the a periodic signal for periodic signal let the period go off to
我们采取了一个周期信号的周期信号让周期走下车来
infinity
无穷大
which case the forty a series coefficients became these
这种情况下，40系列的系数变成了这些
envelope function and incidently mathematically
包络函数和顺便说一句数学
one of the sons ends up going to an integral
其中一个儿子最终要的组成
so what we have then is
还等什么，我们则是
the discrete-time for EA transform
离散时间为EA变换
which is a representation all
这是一个代表所有
and a periodic signal and we have
和一个周期信号，我们有
the synthesis equation which I show as the top equation honest
我诚实的显示为顶部方程的合成公式
transparency and this
透明度和这
is the integral that the four East series
是积分的四个东系列
synthesis equation went to as the period when off to infinity
合成公式去为无穷大的周期时关闭
and we have the corresponding analysis equation
我们有相应的分析方程
which is shown below where this tells us the 48 transform
这是显示在下面这个地方告诉我们，48变换
in effect the envelope all the for a series coefficients
在效果将信封为一系列系数
love that periodic signal in and here
爱是周期信号在这里
represented interns love the a periodic signal
实习生代表爱一个周期信号
okay so we have the analysis equation synthesis equation
好了，我们的分析方程合成公式
there are a number of things to focus
有一些事情要重点
on as you look at this and we'll talk about so its properties
对，你看这和我们谈谈因此它的性能
actually in the next lecture by it sold them the
实际上在下一讲将其卖给他们的
points the I'd like you to think about a focus on
点的我想你想想一家专注于
the fact that now there
事实上，现在已经有
is somewhat have an imbalance or lack of duality between the time-domain and
在某种程度上具有时域和之间的不平衡或缺乏对偶
frequency-domain
频域
x seven witches are a periodic signal is a course
个×7女巫是一个周期性的信号是一个过程
discrete its Fourier transform
它的离散傅里叶变换
Xserve Omega is a function love a continuous variable
Xserve的欧米茄是一个函数爱一个连续变量
Omega is a continuous variable that that
欧米茄是一个连续变量，即
and that is essentially what represents the envelope
而本质上是代表什么的信封
also in the time domain x7 is
也是在时域中的7倍是
a periodic its not a periodic function
周期性它不是一个周期函数
however in the frequency domain remember that the for a series coefficients were
然而，在频域中记住的一系列系数分别
always periodic
总是周期性
well this envelope function then is also periodic
以及这个信封功能，那么也是周期性的
with a period in omega up to par i
用了一段欧米伽达到标准我
what's again the reason for the periodicity it all stems back to the
什么是再次为周期性的原因，一切都源于回
fact
事实
there when we talk about complex exponentials
还有，当我们谈论复指数
and recall back to the early lectures in discrete-time
和召回回到早期讲座离散时间
as the frequency variable covers a range
作为频率可变覆盖范围
all to parlay when you proceed past that range
当你继续过去那种范围全部互通
you simply see the same complex exponentials over and over again
你只需看到相同的复指数一遍又一遍
and so obviously anything that we do with them would have to be periodic
所以显然没有什么我们做与他们就必须定期
in that frequency variable alright notation Lee
在该频率可变好吗李记法
and will again represent the
并且将再次代表
discrete-time Fourier transform here as i indicate here
离散傅里叶变换在这里，因为我在此说明
and sense is a complex function of frequency
和感是频率的复函数
may on occasion want to either represented
有时可能想要么代表
in rectangular form as i indicated this equation
在我指出这个方程直角坐标形式
or in polar for as i indicate in this equation
或极作我表示这个等式
all right let's and look at an example
好吧，让我们看看一个例子
and of course one example that
当然还有一个例子是
we can look at is the one that has kind of been tracking this
大家可以看一下是一种已经跟踪这
through this lecture which is the example
通过本次讲座是例子
love a rectangle now
爱一个矩形现在
the rectangle if we refer back to our
矩形，如果我们翻阅我们
argument love how we get a for a representation for a periodic signal
论点爱我们如何得到一个为一个周期信号的表示
we would form a periodic signal where this is repeated
我们将形成一个周期性的信号，其中该重复
and thats are square wave example as the period goes to infinity
并且那是方波的例子为周期趋于无穷
the forty a transformer this is represented by the envelope
在40的变压器，这是由包络线表示
all those for a series coefficients and that was
所有这些对于一个系列的系数，并且是
are sign an X over sin x function
过罪x函数都签署一个X
which in this particular case for these particular numbers
而在这些特定号码这种特殊情况下
is sin 5 Omega over to
是罪5欧米茄过来
divided by sign Omega over to
通过符号欧米茄交给划分
and notice of course as we would expect
当然通知书，我们期望
that notice that this is a
该通知，这是一个
periodic function all the frequency variable Omega
周期函数的所有频率可变欧米茄
repeating of course with a period up to par
与一期达到标准的重复过程
whereas in the time domain the function was not
而在时域中的功能是不
a periodic function it's a period
周期函数这是一个周期
now let's look at another example
现在让我们来看看另一个例子
in let's look at example
在让我们来看看例子
which is another signal that has
这是一种具有另一种信号
kinda popped its head up from time to time as the lectures have gone along
还挺弹出昂首不时的讲座也水涨船高沿
signal which is another a periodic signal which is a decaying exponential
信号，该信号是另一个的周期性信号，它是一个衰减的指数
of this form with the
这种形式与
factor a chosen between 0&1
因素选定介于0和1
and you can workout the algebra
你可以锻炼代数
at your leisure basically if we substituted to the four EA
在您的休闲基本上如果我们取代四个EA
transform analysis equation its
变换分析方程及其
this summer we evaluate because we have a unit step here
这个夏天我们评估，因为我们这里有一个单位阶跃
which shots this of for and less than zero
该镜头的和小于零此
we can change the limits on the some this then corresponds
我们可以改变对一些这方面则相对应的限制
to the some over an infinite number turns
一些在无限圈数的
geometric series and that as we've seen before
等比数列，而正如我们以前见过
is one divided by one minus a
是除以一减一
you to the minus jail make so
你到零下监狱这样做
let's look at what that looks like
让我们来看看是什么样子
here him then we have again
在这里他那么我们再有
the expression in the time domain
在时域的表达
and the expression in the frequency domain
并且在频域中的表达
and lets in particular focus I N what the magnitude of the Fourier transform
并允许在变换中什么样的傅立叶变换的幅度特别关注
looks like
看起来像
its as we show here
其作为我们在这里展示
and for the particular values
和用于特定值
Ave that I picked namely between 0&1
AVE我捡到即介于0与1
its larger at the origin then it is upon I
其在原点较大的则是在我
and then of course it is periodic
然后当然它是周期性的
and the periodicity is inherent in the Fourier transform in discrete-time
和周期性是固有的傅里叶变换在离散时间变换
so we really might only need to look at this either from minus
所以我们真的可能只需要看看这个无论是从减
fired upon by or from 0 to 2pi
在解雇或从0到2PI
the periodicity of course would imply what the rest at this is for other
当然，周期性将意味着什么，其余在此是其他
values have or make it
值具有或使其
let me also draw your attention at war on it
让我也请你注意在战争中就可以了
the fact dead observed at if
如果在观察到死亡的事实
a were in fact negative then
一个实际上是否定的，则
this value would be less than this value
这个值会小于这个值
and in fact for a negative
而实际上对于负
the magnitude the frequency response would look like this except shifted
幅度，频率响应是这样的，除了转移
by an amount in omega equal the pie
由量的omega等于馅饼
and this example will come up
而这个例子上来了
and play an important role in our discussion next time
并发挥我们的讨论下一次重要的作用
so try to keep it in mind in fact work it out more carefully between
所以要尽量记住它实际上做出来更仔细地之间
now and next time and also if you have a chance
现在和未来的时间，也如果你有机会
focus on this issue love how it looks
围绕这一问题，喜欢它的外观
with a positive is compared with a negative
以积极的与消极相比
okay now we developed the 48 transform
现在没事了，我们开发了48变换
by beginning with the forty a series we did that in continuous time also
由开始的40系列我们做了，在连续的时间也
but I'd like to do now just as we did in continuous-time
但我想现在要做的，就像我们在连续时间做
is now absorb the forty a series
现在吸收了40系列
within the broader framework above the 40 a transport
40运输上面的更广泛框架内
and there are two relationships between the forty a series the Fourier transform
并且有40一系列的傅立叶变换之间的两种关系
which are identical to relationships that we had
这是相同的，我们有关系
in the continuous-time case
在连续时间的情况下
let me remind you dead in
让我提醒你死在
continuous-time we head
连续时间，我们前往
the statement there if we have a periodic signal
那里的语句，如果我们有一个周期信号
that in fact the forty a series coefficients that periodic signal
，事实上，40的一系列系数是周期信号
is proportional to
正比于
the two samples of the Fourier transform
两个样品的傅里叶变换
all one period well
都是一个好时期
in fact thats let me remind you flows
其实那让我来提醒你流
easily from all other things that we've built up
轻松地从我们已经建立了所有其他的事情
so far because of the fact that the for a transformer sexually
到目前为止，因为一个事实，即对于一个变压器的性
by definition love the way we developed it
顾名思义爱我们开发的方式
is what we get as
就是我们得到的
the forty-a series coefficients
第四一系列系数
as we focus on one period and then let the period go off to infinity
因为我们专注于一个周期，然后让内熄灭到无限远
well thats looking at one period before a transformer that then
还有那望着变压器前一个周期的再
is the envelope above the 40 a series coefficients
高于40的一系列系数的包络线
and so in continuous-time we have
所以在连续时间我们也
this relationship and in discrete-time
这种关系和在离散时间
we have precisely the same relationship
我们有完全相同的关系
except that here we're talking about
但此处我们谈论
an integer variable and as opposed to the continuous variable and a period of
整型变量，而相对于连续变量和一段
capital and
资本和
as opposed to a period
相对于一个周期
love t0 okay so
爱T0这么好吗
once again if we returned to
再次，如果我们回到
our example
我们的例子
if or Fri return to a periodic signal
如果星期五或返回到一个周期性信号
we have a periodic signal and we consider
我们有一个周期信号，我们认为
the for EA transform love
在对EA变换的爱
one period the for a series coefficients
一个周期的为一系列系数
this periodic signal are in fact
这个周期信号实际上
samples as stated
样品为表示
mathematically in the bottom equation samples
数学上在底部方程样品
love the four EA transform all
爱的四个EA变换所有
one period so XO makers the for a transformer one period
一个周期这样的XO厂商的一个变压器一个周期
a suitcase at a4e series coefficients at the periodic signal
行李箱在在周期信号A4E级数的系数
and this relationship simply says their related except for a scale factor
而且这种关系只是说他们的相关除了一个比例因子
through samples along the frequency axis
通过沿着频率轴的样本
and and the chorus we saw this
并与合唱，我们看到了这
in the context all our
在上下文中的所有我们
square wave example in a square wave
在方波方波的例子
example we have a periodic signal
例如，我们有一个周期信号
which is a periodic square wave
这是一个周期的方波
and the for EA transform
而对EA变换
a one period in fact represents
其实是一个周期指
the on below and here we have the envelope function
在下面，在这里我们有包络函数
represents the envelope or the forty a series coefficients
表示包络或40的一系列系数
and the for a series coefficients are samples
以及为一系列系数是样本
so what we have been is
所以我们一直是
a relationship back to before a series coefficients from the Fourier transform
关系回到之前从傅立叶级数系数​​变换
that tells us that for periodic signal now
这告诉我们，对于周期信号现在
the periodic signal the for a series coefficients
的周期信号的对一系列系数
are related are samples of the Fourier transform
有相关的是傅里叶变换样本
one period now
1现在期
finally to kinda bring things back in a circle
终于有点带的东西回来了一圈
and exactly identical to what we did it in the continuous-time
和完全相同就是我们在连续时间做到了
case we can finally absorber
情况下，我们终于可以吸收器
the 48 series indiscreet
48系列指手画脚
time we can absorb it into the framework
一次，我们可以吸收到它的框架
all the four EA transport now
现在所有四个EA运输
remember or recall how we did at when
记得还是记得我们是如何在做的时候
re tried to do a similar sort of thing
再试着做一个类似的事情
in continuous-time in continuous-time
在连续时间在连续时间
what we essentially did is
我们基本上做的是
to develop that more less by definition
开发出的定义更加少
we have occurred we have a periodic signal
我们已经发生，我们有一个周期性信号
the periodic signal is represented through 48 series
周期性信号通过48系列为代表
in forty a series coefficients essentially
在40系列基本上系数
when I pointed out at that time was that if we define
当我指出，在当时，如果我们定义
and take it as a definition before a transformer the periodic signal
并把它作为一个变压器之前定义的周期信号
as an impulse train where the amplitudes at the impulses are proportional
作为一个脉冲串，其中振幅的冲动是成正比
to the forty a series coefficients
到40的一系列系数
if we take an impulse train representation
如果我们把一个脉冲串表示
and simply plug it in
并简单地将它插入
to the for EA
在对EA
transform synthesis equation what we end up with
变换合成公式是什么，我们结束了
is the for you see recent this equation
是给你看最近这个等式
so in continuous-time
因此，在连续时间
we bad done
我们做的不好
we had used this definition I love
我们曾用这个定义我爱
the discrete-time up the continuous-time
离散时间最多的连续时间
for EA transform other periodic signal
对EA变换等周期信号
and again in discrete-time it's simply a matter
并再次在离散时间它只是一个问题
love using exactly the same expression
喜欢使用完全相同的表达
and using instead the appropriate
而改用适当的
variables related to discrete-time rather than the variables related to
有关离散时间变量，而不是相关的变量
continuous-time
连续时间
so in discrete-time if we have a periodic signal
因此，在离散时间，如果我们有一个周期性信号
the Fourier transform that periodic signal
傅立叶变换的周期信号
is defined as an impulse train where the
被定义为一个脉冲序列，在其中的
amplitudes up the impulses
幅度高达冲动
are proportional to the forty a series coefficients
正比于40一系列系数
if this expression is substituted into the synthesis equation
如果该表达式代入方程合成
for the 48 transform we will simply that will simply then reduced to
对于48变换，我们将简单地将简单地然后减少到
this synthesis equation for the forty a series
第四十一个系列的合成公式
so wants more returning to
所以希望有更多的回
our example which is the square wave example that we carry through these
我们的例子是，我们贯彻这些方波的例子
lectures
讲座
or through this lecture we can see that
或通过这个讲座，我们可以看到，
really what we're talking about really is a notational change
真的是我们谈论的还真是一个符号变化
here is the four EA here is the periodic signal
这里是四EA这里的周期信号
and below it are the forty a series
和它下面的是40系列
coefficients where I've removed the envelope function just indicate
在那里我已经删除了包络函数的系数只是表明
the airport to the coefficients index of course on the coefficient number
机场当然是对的系数数的系数指数
and so this represents a bar graph and
所以这代表了条形图和
if instead of talking about the for a series coefficients
如果不是在谈论一个级数的系数
what I want to talk about are the
我想谈的是
is the four EA transform the Fourier transform
是四个EA变换傅立叶变换
in essence corresponds to simply redrawing mad
在本质上对应于简单地重画狂
using impulses and using
用冲动和使用
an axis that is essentially
的轴线基本上
index on the fundamental frequency Omega
指数基频欧米茄
rather than on the four EA series coefficient number
而不是在4 EA系列系数数
K
okay in so
还好在这样
to summarize what we've done
总结我们做了什么
is to pretty much parallel
是几乎平行
are somewhat more quickly the kind of development that we went through
有些更迅速，我们通过去的那种发展
for continuous-time representation through complex exponentials
通过复指数连续时间表示法
parallel that for the discrete-time case
平行，对于离散时间情况
and pretty much the conceptual underpinnings that the development are
和几乎概念基础的发展是
identical
相同
in discrete-time and in continuous time
在离散时间和连续时间
we saw there'd their are
我们在那里看到他们的希望是
some major differences are important differences between continuous-time and
一些主要的差异是连续时间之间的重要区别和
discrete-time
离散时间
I'm and the difference essentially
我和本质上的区别
relates to two aspect one aspect is the fact that
涉及2方面中的一个方面是一个事实，即
in discrete-time we have a discrete representation in the time domain
在离散时间，我们有一个离散的表示在时域中
whereas the independent variable in the frequency domain
而在频域中的自变量
is a continuous variable whereas in continuous-time
是一个连续的变量，而在连续时间
for the Fourier transform we had duality between the time-domain and
对于傅里叶变换，我们不得不将时域和对偶之间
frequency-domain
频域
the other very important difference tied back to the difference between complex
回接到复杂的区别另一非常重要的区别
exponentials continuous-time and discrete-time
指数函数的连续时间和离散时间
in continuous-time complex exponentials as you very the frequency
在连续时间复指数作为你非常频
generate distinct
产生不同
time functions in discrete-time as you very the frequency
在离散时间的功能，非常的频率
once you've covered a frequency interval to pie
一旦你所投保的频率间隔馅饼
then you've seen all the ones there are two see there are no more
那么你已经看到所有的人有两个看有没有更多的
in this in a fact imposes a periodicity
在这一个事实强加的周期性
on the 48 domain representation of discrete-time signals
上的离散时间信号的48个域表示
and those so those differences and of course lots the similarities
而那些使这些分歧，当然还有很多的相似之处
will surface both as we use this representation
将表面既作为我们使用这种表示
and as we develop for the property
和我们开发的物业
in the next lecture what will do is
在下一讲什么可以做的是
to focus and again on the Fourier transform the discrete-time Fourier
聚焦并再次对傅立叶变换的离散时间傅里叶
transform
改造
develop or eliminate so love the property serv the trip or a transform
制定或消除这么爱的财产SERV行程或变换
and then see how these properties can be used
再看看这些属性如何使用
for a number of things for example how the properties as they were in
对于一些事情，例如如何为他们在性能
continuous-time
连续时间
can be used to efficiently
可以用于有效地
generate the solution and analyze when your constant coefficient difference
生成解决方案和分析时，你常系数差异
equations
方程
and then beyond that the concepts of
然后超出的概念
filtering and modulation and
滤波和调制
the both the properties and interpretation which will very strongly
两者的性质和解释这将非常强烈
parallel
并行
the kinds of developments along those lines that we did in the last night
该种发展沿着那些我们在昨晚线
thank you
谢谢